本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧字幕 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
翻译：小松狮    Silmar    夜    诺米    nana
时间轴：虫不知    蛐蛐     特效：Will
■
校对：小路    蛐蛐      后期：冰河       监制：蛐蛐
我们来分析一下
Let's break it down.
氢元素  人体中含有多少
Hydrogen. What does that give us?
用摩尔数值表示吗  有63%
By mole? We're looking at 63%.
63吗
63?
占得很多啊
That is a big bite.
下一个是  氧元素
My next step's gotta be oxygen.
26%
26%.
26  以上两种元素组成了水
26. There you have your water.
-碳  9%  -碳  9
- Carbon. 9%.  - Carbon. 9.
-总共是98%  -没错
- For a total of 98%?  - Right.
-氮  1.25%  -1.25
-Nitrogen 1.25%.  - 1.25.
这样总共99.25
That brings it to 99 and a quarter.
剩下就该是微量元素了
Which only leaves you with the trace elements
接下来我们要见证神奇啦
down with the maggic happens.
等一下  钙有多少
Oh, wait a minute. What about calcium?
钙可不是微量元素啊
Calcium's not a trace.
骨头里可都是钙啊
Got a whole skeleton to account for.
-你是这样想的  对吧  -没错
- You would think, right?  - Right.
钙  钙元素只有0.25%
Calcium. Calcium is only 0.25%.
什么  这么少
What? That low?
真的吗
Seriously?
天哪  没想到只有这么少
Damn, I never would have thought that.
好的  铁有多少呢
Okay, so where does Iron fit in?
铁  没错
Iron. Wow, okay.
0.00004%
0.00004%.
什么
What?
没有铁  可没法合成血红蛋白
You can't have hemoglobin without Iron.
看来用不了多少
Apparently, it don't take much.
是啊  继续
No, it don't. Go figure.
-钠  -钠  0.04
- Sodium.  - Sodium? 0.04.
-磷  0.19  -0.19  这就对了
-Phosphorus? 0.19  -0.19. There we go.
这样的话  所有的元素
So, the whole thing...
加起来总共
Adds up to...
99.888042%
99.888042%.
还有0.111958%
We are 0.111958%...
少了
Shy.
应该已经全了才对
Supposedly that's everything.
不知道  我只是
I don't know. I just... I just...
觉得少了什么  不是吗
Just seems like something's missing, doesn't it?
人体内应该还有别的什么
There got to be more to a human being than that.
绝
命
毒
师
第一季
第三集
我讨厌这双鞋
I hate these shoes.
穿着这鞋就好像是
These shoes make me look like
要去给人换便盆一样
I should be changing bedpans,
好像我就应该端着汤
like I should be squeaking around bringing soup
喂给恶心的老头子喝
to some disgusting old person,
然后再搭公车回去照看16只猫
then take the bus home to my 16 cats.
那你干嘛还穿着
Then why are you wearing them?
我喜欢它的足弓垫
I like their support.
我的足弓恰好很拱
My arches happen to be extremely archy.
唷  怎么啦
Yo. What's up?
两分钟以后打给我好吗
Hey, can you call me, like, in two minutes?
谢了  拜拜
Thanks. Bye.
我去接个电话
Gotta go take this.
女的
Female?
路易斯
Louis.
这好像不关你的事吧
Not like it's any of your business, though.
快点就行
Just be quick about it.
还有  别再说"唷"了
Oh, and, um, please don't say yo.
你不知道我有多讨厌这词
You can't know how much I hate that.
你有个地方没刷到
You missed a... spot right there.
你确定能爬梯子吗
Should you be up on that ladder?
欢迎你上来接我的班
You know, you're more than welcome to take over for me up here.
我不明白  干嘛不让沃尔特来做
I don't see why you don't just get Walt to do it.
确实是个主意
Yeah. There's an idea.
最近我正在写短篇小说
So, I'm working on this new short story,
想塑造一个吸毒的人物
and there's this stoner character in it.
我想要
I'm trying to, um...
事实上  我是想问你
Well, you know, actually, let me back up.
你在大学里
You've smoked your
抽过大麻  对吗
fair share of pot in college, didn't you?
我是说  你至少试过吧
I mean, you at least tried it.
承认吧
Come on.
我可能是试过  为什么问这个
I perhaps tried it. Why?
你还记得  大麻对你的情绪有影响吗
Do you remember it having an effect on your mood,
像是性情大变  或者别的
like changing it in any major way, or...
我觉得我变得更严肃了
It made me more serious.
真的吗
Really?
因为我只记得
Because I mostly remember
抽了以后会飘飘欲仙而已
it made me light-headed. That's about it.
我只是想知道  大麻会不会
I was just wondering if it maybe could...
我在这个人物上有点卡住了
You know, it's just a character thing I'm stuck on.
别放在心上
Never mind.
小沃尔特吸大麻了吧
Walter Jr.'s on pot?
什么  不  不是
What? No! No.
你怎么会这么想
What would make you even...
他从哪弄来的
Where's he getting it from?
-玛丽  -说真的  是不是那个叫路易斯的
- Marie.  - Seriously. Is it this Louis person?
你打算怎么做
What are you going to do about this?
你看着我的眼睛  听我说
You need to look me in the eye.
我真的只是在问关于
I am strictly asking about
我在写的小说的事  仅此而已
a story that I am writing. That's all.
我对天发誓  小沃尔特没有吸毒
Right hand to God, Walter Jr. is not on pot.
至少据我所知没有
Certainly not as far as I know.
据你所知没有
Not as far as you know?
玛丽
Marie.
看着我
Look at me.
转过来看着我
Hey, turn around and look at me.
这  这东西
This... This here...
我对头号仇敌也不会这么干
I wouldn't do this to my worst enemy.
太耻辱了
This is degrading.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你希望我会放你一马
You hope I'll make it easy on you
就这么算了  是吧
and just drop them, don't you?
但我不会的
Well, I won't.
所以要么杀了我  要么放了我
So either kill me or let me go.
你不适合干这行  沃尔特
You don't have it in you, Walter.
你怎么知道我名字的
How do you know my name?
杰西
Jesse.
是他告诉埃米利奥和我的
He told Emilio and me.
他来卖你那冰毒的时候
When he came by to sell your meth?
怎么  你威胁他了
So what? You threaten him, huh?
-毒打他了  -根本用不着
- Did you beat it out of him?  - Not even close.
他还跟你说什么了
What else did he tell you?
所有你能想到的事
Pretty much everything you can think of.
你是他的高中老师
How you were his high school teacher.
讲二氧化碳的时候在课堂上
How one time you taught about carbon dioxide
做葡萄汽水
by making grape soda in class.
你有个儿子轻微智障
How you have a son who's retarded,
或者残疾之类的
or in a wheelchair or something.
这应该不算新鲜事吧
This shouldn't come across as some news flash.
你的同伙
That partner of yours...
嘴巴不严实
He's got a big mouth.
沃尔特  我不知道你是怎么看待自己的
Walter, I don't know what you think you're doing here,
但是相信我  这行当不适合你
but trust me, this line of work doesn't suit you.
所以我应该放你走
So I should just let you go, then?
给你开锁  祝你一路顺风吗
Just unlock you and adios, huh?
我看你别无他法
I don't see what real choice you have
不然就得狠下心肠杀我
if it's between that and cold-blooded murder.
此外
Besides...
楼上那位才是大麻烦
Your real problem is sitting upstairs.
有人
Occupied!
我这正费劲呢
Hey, yo, I'm trying to pinch one off in here!
给点私人空间  行吗
Just give me some privacy, would ya?
到底干嘛
What the hell, man?
你干什么
What are you doing, man?
-混蛋  -你告诉他我名字
- You asshole!  - You told him my name.
-谁说的  他自己  -我的名字  在哪儿工作
- Says who? Him?  - My name, where I work.
-还跟他讲我儿子  -别碰我
- You told him about my son!  - Don't touch me!
-该死的混球  -不  给我
- Damn junkie!  - No, give me that!
迟了  我要把它冲到厕所里  你就看着吧
Too late! This is going down the toilet. Watch it go!
值4万呢  你个蠢货
No, that's worth 40 grand, you stupid shit.
你都抽光了就啥也不值
It's worth nothing when you smoke it all.
从马桶上起来
Get off the toilet.
Get off the toilet!
停下
Stop it!
不  没门
No! No way!
你往哪儿走
What the hell do you think you're going?
-闪开  神哪  -我们有活要干
- Back off, man! Jesus!  - We've got work to do!
你有活要干  我的做完了
No, you got work to do. I did my part.
你说我花了两个小时清理的
You mean that obscenity that I spent
那堆恶心东西吗
the last two hour clearning up?
-都是拜你所赐  -滚你妈的蛋
- That is your contribution!  - Yo! Kiss my pink ass, man!
我也不像这么做
I didn't ask for any of this!
我还怎么在这住下去
How am I supposed to live here now, huh?
我的房子整个一股香港脚和干洗剂味儿
My whole house smells like toe cheese and dry cleaning.
因为你不听我指挥
Because you didn't follow my instructions!
万岁  希特勒
Oh, well, heil Hitler, bitch.
我给你说道说道吧
And let me tell you something else.
我们抛过硬币的  记得吗
We flipped a coin, okay?
我们俩
You and me.
You and me!
抛硬币是神圣的
Coin flip is sacred.
该死
Damn it.
地下室里有活等着你
Your job is waiting for you in that basement,
是硬币决定的
as per the coin.
快他妈的动手
Fucking do it already.
她是这么说的
That's what she said.
对  我想那个我们有
Yeah, I think we have some of those.
对  你得试试
Yeah, you'll have to...
-你好  -可能吧  我不清楚
- Hello.  - Maybe. I don't know.
你好  这款有黑色吗
Excuse me. Do you have these in black?
总之  就像我说的
Anyway, so like I was saying,
几天前的某个晚上我去参加了派对
I went to the party the other night.
对  托尼在那
Yeah, Tony was there.
你去哪儿了  我两小时前就给你打电话
Hey, where have you been? I called you two hours ago.
对不起  宝贝儿  我有点忙  什么事
Sorry, baby. I'm kinda busy here. What's up?
大事  是个敏感问题
Kind of a lot, actually, and it's a delicate subject,
你得认真听
so I need you to focus and...
坐下  快坐下
Hey, sit down! Sit down!
该死的  汉克
Damn it, Hank.
对不起  宝贝  我
Well, sorry, babe. I'm just...
我这边有点麻烦
I'm kind of in the middle of something here.
坐下  屁股着地坐
Sit down! Sit your ass down!
懂了没  你也是  坐下
Comprende? You, too! Sit down!
坐下(墨西哥语)
Siéntate
好了  宝贝儿  什么事
I'm back, baby. What's up?
是小沃尔特
Walter Jr.
他怎么了
Yeah, what about him?
大麻
Marijuana.
-他吸大麻  -胡扯
- He's smoking it.  - Bullshit.
他妈妈似乎这么觉得
Excuse me. His own mother seems to think so.
-斯凯勒告诉你的  -她暗示我了
- Skyler told you that?  - She inferred it.
暗示吗
She inferred it, huh?
她强烈的暗示  就像说
She strongly inferred it, like...
"医生  我一个朋友有勃起功能障碍"
"Doctor, my friend suffers from erectile dysfunction."
好了  你得跟他谈谈
Please, come on already. I want you to talk to him.
该沃尔特跟他谈  斯凯勒更好
Walt should talk to him. Skyler, better yet.
她会打得他满街跑的
She'll kick his butt up and down the block.
我认为应该你去
I think it ought to be you.
给他讲讲吓人的故事
You know, tell him some horror stories.
或许给他看些尸检照片
Maybe show him some autopsy pictures.
吸毒过量的尸检照片吗  算了吧
What, autopsy for a pot overdose? Come on.
我不知道  宝贝儿  只是
I don't know, baby. It's just that, you know I mean...
我觉得他爸来做更合适
I figure his dad should be the one doing this thing,
不是吗
don't you think?
汉克  他敬重你
Hank, he respects you.
好吧  行了  听着
Yeah, all right. Well, listen,
我下班后过去一趟
I'll swing by the place after work.
好  把他吓乖
Good. Scare him straight.
我的奖励呢
Where's my sugar?
抱歉  女士
Excuse me, ma'am. ma'am.
试鞋要穿丝袜
You need to be wearing footies before you try those on.
我脚干净得很
I'm extremely clean.
如果穿的话我会很感激的
Yeah, well, I'd really appreciate it.
对不起  我会查的
Hey, sorry about that. Yeah, I'll check.
知道吗  上周我给你囤了一双  灰色的
You know, I hid a pair for you last week, gray ones...
觉得怎么样
What do you think?
什么
About what?
这地方看上去不错吧
This look like a nice place?
不  不觉得
No, not really.
你想住这里吗
Think you'd like to live here?
不
No.
-你确定吗  -对  非常确定
- You sure about that?  - Yeah, pretty sure.
我以为我们是去酷圣石(世界知名冰淇淋)
I thought we were going to Cold Stone creamery.
对  绕了点路而已
Well, a little detour.
我想着咱们过来一趟
Figured we'd come over here and
看看大麻的行情
check out how the was marijuana.
我们管这里叫水晶宫
This here's what we call the Crystal Palace.
你知道什么人住在宫里吗  瘾君子
Now you know who lives in the palace? Meth-heads.
肮脏的  讨厌的  瘾君子
Nasty, skeevy, meth-heads
为了口毒品  他们能让自己的奶奶出来卖淫
who'd sell their grandma's coochie for a hit.
-你觉得这好笑吗  好笑吧  -是
- Oh, you think that's funny? That's funny, huh?  - Yeah.
我来跟你说说  这帮可怜的废物
Well, let me tell you something. Every last one of these
是怎么染上毒瘾的
miserable wastes of skin got started. How?
-你觉得他们是怎么抽上的  -我不知道
- How do you think they got started?  - I don't know.
你觉得他们之前
What do you think it was they were
都是抽什么毕业的
all doing before their graduated in their...
在注射冰毒之前
to shooting meth in their dicks?
诱导性毒品
A gateway drug.
我们这么叫它
That's what we call it.
我可以肯定地告诉你
Dollars to doughnuts, and I shit you not,
所谓的诱导性毒品就是大麻
that gateway drug was marijuana.
概无例外
Every time.
-你明白吗  -明白了
- You understand?  - Um, Yeah.
你干嘛跟我说这些
So why are you telling me this?
因为我爱你  你这个混小子
Cause I love you, you little bastard.
我也年轻过  知道吗
Hey, I was young once, you know?
这世界太乱  知道吗
The world's a messed up place, you know?
曾经有一次
You know, there was this...
有一次当
This one time when... hey!
你
Hey! Hey, you!
叫你呢  公主
Yeah, you, princess!
到这边来
Get over here!
别逼我下车
Don't make me get out of the car!
看我怎么说的
See what I'm talking about.
我手里没货  明白吗
I ain't holding, okay?
我让你说话了吗
Did I say you could open your mouth?
把手拿开
And hands off the car.
另一边  到另一边去
Other side. Go around the other side.
跟我朋友聊聊
Talk to my friend here.
甜心  你叫什么啊
What's your name, sweetheart?
-温蒂  -温蒂
- Wendy.  - Wendy, huh?
温蒂  一次开价多少
How much you charge for a windy, Wendy?
我可不和他做  他还是个毛孩子
I ain't doing him. He's a kid.
天  我问你这个了吗
Jesus, was that my question.
别想太多  小心伤脑子
Don't think so hard. It's gonna hurt your brain.
你是用抽的还是用针管
Are you on the pipe or the needle?
没有  都不是
Nothing. Neither.
给我们看看你的牙齿
Show us your teeth, huh?
快啊  温蒂  给咱们秀下你皓白的牙齿
Come on, Wendy, let's see those pearly whites.
上帝  看到没
Oh, god. See that?
抽的  肯定是
Pipe. Definitely.
绝对  绝对是用抽的
Big time. Big time on the pipe.
-你有事要问温蒂吗  -不  没有
- You got something you wanna ask Wendy?  - No, not really.
温蒂  你还吸什么别的吗
You ever smoke anything else, Wendy?
香肠可不算
Sausages don't count.
说正经的
Seriously.
跟我朋友说说你是怎么吸上的
Tell my friend here how you got started.
你以前可能是童子军
You probably used to be, what, like, a girl scouter
不然就在教堂唱诗班唱歌
or probably sang in a church choir?
你呢  残废吗
What do you like, handicap.
他打橄榄球时把腿弄断了
He broke his leg playing football.
他可是四分卫
He's a qb.
胳臂跟榴弹炮一样猛
Got an arm like a howitzer.
告诉我  温蒂  你抽大麻吗
Tell me, Wendy, do you smoke pot?
-干嘛  你有货  -行了  滚吧
- Why, you got some?  - All right. Hoof it. Get lost.
滚开  先警告你
Get out of here. Hey, fair warning!
让我撞见就逮捕你
Next time I'm gonna bust you.
你作何感想
So what do you think?
很棒
Cool.
关门  关门
Shut the door. Shut the door.
锁上  锁上
Lock it. Lock it.
那他妈是谁
Who the hell was that?
一条子和某个橄榄球运动员跟我瞎扯
A cop and some football player messing with me.
他们问起我了吗
They ask about me? huh?
没有  我想他们是想要大麻
No. I think they just wanted pot.
见鬼  我没拿我的麦根沙士
Oh, shit. I left my root beer.
让他活着
Let him live.
这样做是道德的
It's the moral thing to do.
或许他能听进道理  创伤后应激
不要让你良心不安
Won't be able to live with yourself.
杀人是犯法的
Murder is wrong!
杀了他  要是放走他  他会杀你全家
Kill him. He'll kill you entire family if you let him go.
你好
Hello.
亲爱的  是我
Hey, sweetie, it's me.
我很抱歉
Listen, I'm so sorry.
我忘了时间
The time, it just completely got away from me there.
我的错  我的错  博格丹让我加班
My fault. My fault. Bogdan just kept me here late,
你知道的  盘点库存  还有
you know, doing some inventory, and...
我  我应该
I've... I should have just...
你说的对  我应该学会说  "不"
You know, you're right. I gotta learn to say, you know, "No"!
但是
But, um...
斯凯  在听吗
Sky? You there?
你是在洗车店吗
You're at the car wash?
对
Yeah.
我对此深表怀疑
I seriously doubt that,
因为你两星期前辞职了
Since you quit two weeks ago.
我打过电话给博格丹找你
I called Bogdan, looking for you.
他的话令我大吃一惊
Quite an earful he gave me.
听着
Listen...
听我说  我会回家去的  回家再谈
Listen, I'll come home, and we'll talk about it.
我不这么想  沃尔特
I don't think so, Walt.
亲爱的
Honey.
不管你在哪
Wherever you are...
你就在那过夜好了
Why don't you just stay there tonight?
斯凯勒
Skyler?
沃尔特
Walter!
下面的快饿死啦
Kind of hungry down here!
该死
Damn.
我还以为你就此长眠了呢
I didn't think you were coming back.
我昏过去多久
How long was I out?
10到15分钟的样子
10, 15 minutes.
我从来没见过咳嗽能把自己给摔了
I've never seen someone knock themselves out just by coughing.
你也中了和我一样的毒气吗
You breathe in the same thing you used on me?
我得了肺癌
I've got lung cancer.
我再给你做个三明治
I'll go make you another sandwich.
放心吃吧
It's safe.
没放毒药
There's no poison.
是吗
Yeah?
如果你要杀我
Because that'd be the way to do it...
这可是好机会
if you're gonna do it.
我觉得也是
I suppose it would.
我是说  你毕竟是个化学家
I mean, you being a chemist and all.
那么
So...
那个名字
That name...
疯狂小八
Krazy-8...
我一定要这么称呼你吗
Do I really have to call you that?
我无意冒犯  不过
I mean, no offense, but...
你有真名吗
Don't you have a real name?
多明戈
Domingo.
是星期天的意思  对吗
That's "Sunday", right?
如果你不介意的话  我就这么叫你
I'd rather call you that, if you don't mind.
可以  随便你
Yeah, whatever.
我自己也说不上喜欢这名字
I can't say I ever liked it much.
那么  多明戈
So, Domingo...
你是本地人  还是外地来的
Are you from around town here or someplace else?
沃尔特  你多了解我点
Walter, you getting to know me
并不意味着对我下手就容易些
is not gonna make it easier for you to kill me.
你要知道  我可不怕
Not that I mind, you understand.
你一直跟我说
You know, you keep telling me
我不适合这工作  或许吧
that I don't have it in me. Well, maybe.
也可能不对
But maybe not.
我一直在找不杀你的理由
I sure as hell I'm looking for any reason not to.
哪怕一点也行
I mean, any good reason at all.
忽悠我吧
Sell me.
回答我刚才那个问题
Tell me what it is.
我想应该先向你保证
I guess I'd start off by promising that,
如果你放我走  我不会来追杀你
if you let me go, I won't come after you.
你会平安没事
That you'd be safe.
我想说我们之间发生的一切
I guess I'd say what happened between us...
就当从没发生过
never happened.
我们把这事忘得一干二净  对大家都有好处
And what's best for both parties is we forget all about it.
但你觉得谁会在这种情况下
But you know that anybody in my situation
做这样的承诺
Would make promise like that?
就算有
And though in my case they happen to be true,
你也不能确信真假
you'd never know for sure.
我还能跟你说什么呢
So what else can I tell you?
我不知道
I don't know.
但是你得说服我
But you gotta convince me.
不然的话你哪都别想去
And you're going nowhere until you do.
别  别  别
Hey, yeah. Yeah.
我是本地人
I'm from here in town, man.
阿尔布开克人  土生土长的本地人
ABQ. Born and bred.
从没出去过
Never left.
在新墨西哥州立大学攻读工商管理
Studied business administration over at UNM,
并获得学位
got my degree.
真的吗
Really?
那个在毒品交易时能派上用场吗
Does that come in handy in the drug trade?
根本没用
It doesn't hurt.
本来我想学音乐的
I was gonna study music originally.
还想考奥柏林或伯克利音乐学院的
Maybe even try out for Oberlin or Berklee.
我爸爸劝我放弃
My pops talked me out of it.
他说除非我跟某些狗屁摇滚歌星混
Said there was no money in it unless
不然的话  赚不了钱
I wind up some bullshit rock star.
而我压根就没有任何机会
And I didn't have a snowball chance of that, man.
你爸爸是干什么的
What does your dad do?
他在梅诺尔有家坦皮科家具店
He owns Tampico furniture over on Menaul.
等等  我知道那地方
Wait a minute. I know that place.
等等
Wait a minute. That's...
就是那个
That's that...
他们以前在深夜
They used to have those late-night...
-放那些无聊广告  -没错  -就是他
- Those stupid commercials. - Yeah. - That's him.
-他开了30多年  -等等
- He's been doing them for over 30 years.  - Wait a minute.
那个怎么唱来着  是不是
How did it go? It was, uh...
等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait. It was...
别让购物伤透脑筋
Don't let shopping strain your brain-o.
来唱唱这首小曲
Just sing this short refrain-o.
我们的家具都很棒
Our furniture is bueno.
店名叫做坦皮科
Tampico is the name-o.
好傻的歌
Pretty moronic.
不过你能怎么办
But what can you do?
印象太深刻了
It did tend to stick in your head.
家族里的音乐家  是你写的吗
Did you write that, being the musician of the family?
当然不是
Hell, no, man.
是我的疯子叔叔埃里克斯写的
It was my crazy uncle Alex.
他在酒吧里唱  用来泡妞的
He sings it at bars, trying to pick up on women.
他认为  这首歌好像在说
In his mind, it's like saying,
我写下了通往天堂的阶梯
"I wrote stairway to heaven."
等等  坦皮科家具
Wait a minute. Tampico furniture.
我记得我儿子出生时
I think when my son was born that
在那买的摇篮车
we bought his bassinet there.
我们不卖摇篮车的
We don't sell bassinets there.
有更特别的
It's more special deal.
我们的确卖过婴儿床
We did use to sell cribs.
婴儿床  可能吧  婴儿车
Oh. Well, a crib, then, okay? Crib.
对  没的  我记起来了
Yeah. No, I remember that.
其实
In fact,
我记得那些广告里那个是你爸爸
I remember recognizing your dad from those commercials.
虽然他在真实生活里
Although he wasn't...
一点也不友好
anywhere near as friendly in real life.
对  一点都没错
Yeah, no shit.
他是不是想给你提供延长保修啊
Did he try selling you that extended warranty?
好像是的
Yeah, he probably did.
而且我也傻兮兮的买了
And I was probably dumb enough to buy it.
他就看中那个
Yeah, that was his big thing.
你向他要一杯水
You ask him for a glass of water,
他就跟你说  要冰块就得延长保修期
he'll tell you you need an extended warranty on the ice.
-你也在那里工作吗  -一直在
- So did you work there, too?  - Only my whole life,
直到我跟他说"操你妈"  然后不干了
up until the day I said "fuck you" and quit.
那么
So, uh...
16年前你多大
16 years ago, how old would you have been?
放学后  相信我  我就在那儿
It was after school. Trust me, I was there.
可能还给你打过电话
Might have even helped ring you up.
你和延长保修期证都婴儿车里
You and your extended warranty on the crib.
世界真小啊
Small world.
是啊
That it is.
这就是我们走过的路
The paths we take, huh?
要吗
You'd like...
你...
You...
杰西知道你得了癌症吗
Jesse know you got cancer?
除了你没人知道
No one but you.
家人也不知道吗
Not your family?
不知道
No.
为什么不说
Why not?
不知道怎么开口
Not a conversation I'm even remotely ready to have.
所以你才做冰毒吗
That's why you're cooking meth?
想给家人留下笔钱
You want to leave money for your family.
要是你现在放了我  我就给你写张支票
Hell, I'll write you a check right now if you let me go.
就像我说的  沃尔特
Like I said, Walter,
这行当根本不适合你
this line of work doesn't suit you.
事情无法挽回之前尽早抽身
Get out before it's too late.
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do.
你心里知道的
Yeah. you do.
我去拿钥匙
I'll get the key.
别这样  别这样
No, don't do this. Don't do this.
你何必如此
Why are you doing this?
何必如此
why are you doing this?
你的决定是对的  沃尔特
You're doing the right thing, Walter.
你能不能...
Do you mind to...
那你没生气吧
So... you're not angry?
你什么意思
How do you mean?
生气
Angry?
没有
No.
宽以待人  伙计
Live and let live, man.
那是可以理解的
That's very understanding.
随便吧
Whatever, man.
我只想回家
I just want to go home.
我也是
Me, too.
把我解开  沃尔特
Unlock me, Walter.
那瞬间我...
The moment I do...
你想用那个破盘子戳死我吗
Are you gonna stick me with that broken piece of plate?
抱歉  抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
对不起  对不起  非常抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry...
对不起
I'm sorry.
真对不起
I'm so sorry.
有人吗
Hello?
下面有人吗
Anybody down here?
各位
Everybody!
大家都坐在自己的位置上
I need you all to take your seats.
请坐好  谢谢
Settle down, please. Thank you.
我知道怀特先生
I understand that Mr. White
今早有点不舒服
is feeling a little under the weather this morning,
所以今天由我来代课
so you folks are going to have to be making do with me today.
我们今天
And we are going to be watching
准备看一段很有意思有关碳的影片
a very interesting video on carbon.
非常重要的元素
Very important stuff.
-你们怎么想  -这个是制毒点  肯定是
- So what do you think?  - It's a cook site. Gotta be.
没人会碰巧经过这鬼地方的
Nobody came way the hell out here just to buy.
火灾可能是由于事故引起的
Fire there could have started by accident.
看起来不像是故意毁灭证据
Don't look like it was meant to destroy evidence.
有好几条双轨道通向那条路
Got a couple of dually tracks headed away towards the road.
怎么  难道他们是在露天实验
So, what, they're in some kind of camper slash lab.
他们不小心放了火  然后就消失了
They accidentally start a fire, and everybody f.o.'s?
怎么不能啊
Yeah, why not?
为什么那个头发跟胶一样的家伙留下车呢
Except why would that little hair-gelled shit leave his car?
哎呀呀  格米
I-yi-yi, Gomie!
素质都大不如前了
It's a culture in decline.
又丰富又充满活力的修养
It's a rich and vibrant culture.
车上下颠簸
It's a car that jumps up and down.
怎么了
What the hell?
你们习惯做征服者了  老天爷
You people used to be conquistadors, for christ's sake.
闻着像达卡黑工厂
Smells like a drakkar noir factory in here.
我已经检查过了
I already searched it.
你只是在浪费时间
You're wasting your time.
别找了
Give it up.
这要是辆迷惑人的车辆
If this here's a trap car,
你这么干  什么也找不出
it's gonna take more than your dumb white ass to find it.
我可是寻密老手  伙计
You are talking to the trap car master, my friend.
我是数牙签的雨人
I'm rain man counting his toothpicks.
对  你跟雨人一样
Yeah, you're like rain man.
是弱智
Retarded.
好了  宝贝儿
Yeah, baby.
-看看  能人儿  -混蛋
- Hello, zippy.  - Asshole!
看起来像是冰毒  但是
I'd say that looks like meth, but it's...
这颜色也太他妈的白了
It's too damn white.
知道我在想什么吗  格米
You know what I'm thinking, Gomie.
有人灭了我们的线人
Somebody croaked our snitch.
探员
Hey, agents!
有什么发现吗
You got something?
我也不知道  只是
I don't know. Just...
难道看起来不像
Just doesn't it seem like...
缺了什么吗
Something's missing?
灵魂呢
What about the soul?
灵魂
The soul.
除了化学再无它物
There's nothing but chemistry here.
斯凯勒
Skyler.
我有事要告诉你
There's something I have to tell you.